<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Direct Support for Ukraine]]></title><description><![CDATA[Direct Support for U]]></description><link>https://www.directsupportforukraine.com/news-updates</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:23:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.directsupportforukraine.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Examples of the need]]></title><description><![CDATA[21/4/22 Four examples from the sixty families she cares for Yura, age 14. He has cerebral palsy and lives with his mum on the 3rd floor...]]></description><link>https://www.directsupportforukraine.com/post/examples-of-the-need</link><guid isPermaLink="false">629749713823c749b5bf5e33</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:12:03 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>johnajmullett</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>21/4/22</p><h2>Four examples from the sixty families she cares for </h2><ul>
  <li>Yura, age 14. He has cerebral palsy and lives with his mum on the 3rd floor of an old building without an elevator. During air raids, his mum cannot carry him downstairs to basement. So since the war started, Yura spends most of his time in the corridor without windows (after the bombshelter, this is the safest place to be as it is made of structural/carrying walls). Poltava has been bombed many times.</li>
  <li>Karolina, age 6, has cerebral palsy and a lot of issues with her knees (she already had 3 operations). Used to live in Kyiv, capital of Ukraine, but when the bombing started, she and her mother moved to Fastov, a town not far from Kyiv. But even there, they had rockets flying over their heads and once it was so close, they thought that was the end. The rocket exploded at the nearby factory.</li>
  <li>Vlad, age 18. Cerebral palsy, very small for his age – only 110 cm tall, very skinny too. And yet, he smiles a lot. He lives with his mother in a house that doesn’t have running water (mom has to get it from the well), the food is cooked on a fire stove which mom needs to bring wood for. Vlad’s mother has been an orphan since age 8.</li>
  <li>Vanya, age 12. Blind, partially deaf, cerebral palsy. He is learning to stand with foot splints. Can hear only very loud noises. Loves music.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Special needs children trapped in a war - Yuliya's work  ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nataliya's Introduction to Yuliya 22/4/22 From Nataliya Yuliya has been supporting children and young adults with very special needs in...]]></description><link>https://www.directsupportforukraine.com/post/your-title-what-s-your-blog-about</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62409ca8fb4ac1d1195d2cc5</guid><category><![CDATA[People who we are supporting]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 17:19:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_08788f6f95724dafafaae5b1a26f2b3e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_315,h_268,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>johnajmullett</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Nataliya's Introduction to Yuliya</h2><p>22/4/22</p><h4>From Nataliya</h4><p>Yuliya has been supporting children and young adults with very special needs in Ukraine for several years now. Their life has always been difficult, but current war made things almost impossible (how can a single mum move a 14 year old bed ridden boy to a bomb shelter on short notice?). The other day we were having a late evening call (she had spent whole day trying to find adult nappies in different humanitarian aid centers – all to no avail) and she promised to write more about “her” children later after the conversation (I do notice the tenderness in her voice as she says "her"). Late at night, I get a brief message that there were more rockets flying by Yuliya’s house and she had to organize a sleeping space for herself and her daughter in the corridor. Next day, despite broken sleep, she sends me a long list of needs of families she supports… and now it is my turn to loose sleep… because of everything these families are going through.</p>
<p>I hope we can help.</p><hr><p>21/4/22</p><h2>Four examples from the sixty families she cares for </h2><ul>
  <li>Yura, age 14. He has cerebral palsy and lives with his mum on the 3rd floor of an old building without an elevator. During air raids, his mum cannot carry him downstairs to basement. So since the war started, Yura spends most of his time in the corridor without windows (after the bombshelter, this is the safest place to be as it is made of structural/carrying walls). Poltava has been bombed many times.</li>
  <li>Karolina, age 6, has cerebral palsy and a lot of issues with her knees (she already had 3 operations). Used to live in Kyiv, capital of Ukraine, but when the bombing started, she and her mother moved to Fastov, a town not far from Kyiv. But even there, they had rockets flying over their heads and once it was so close, they thought that was the end. The rocket exploded at the nearby factory.</li>
  <li>Vlad, age 18. Cerebral palsy, very small for his age – only 110 cm tall, very skinny too. And yet, he smiles a lot. He lives with his mother in a house that doesn’t have running water (mom has to get it from the well), the food is cooked on a fire stove which mom needs to bring wood for. Vlad’s mother has been an orphan since age 8.</li>
  <li>Vanya, age 12. Blind, partially deaf, cerebral palsy. He is learning to stand with foot splints. Can hear only very loud noises. Loves music.</li>
</ul><hr><p>21/4/22</p><h2>Examples of the items that are urgently needed</h2><ul>
  <li>Adult nappies size S or M (Seny or Tena brands), some children use children size nappies (up to 30 kg)</li>
  <li>Disposable bed pads (90x60 or bigger), wet wipes</li>
  <li>Hygiene care products for bed ridden patients (nappy creams, gels for washing and shampoos)</li>
  <li>Food – both general (pureed baby food and formula) and specialized (protein mixes, gluten and dairy free products), juices, fruits</li>
  <li>General food – for both mothers and children.  Some of the children are able to eat basic food if it is blended.</li>
  <li>Physiotherapy - usually 10-14 days, requirements vary depending on diagnosis</li>
  <li>Medicines - mothers have to find and order medications themselves – these are often not provided by the state</li>
  <li>Basic sanitary hygiene products for mothers and their teenage daughters (sanitary pads, tampons)</li>
  <li>Clothing and shoes</li>
  <li>Wheelchairs and specialized care equipment (for example, loungers for bathtubs – to be able to give bath to a disabled teenager)</li>
  <li>Basic white goods (most mothers cannot afford to buy even most basic kitchen appliances – they live with broken or very old electric equipment; often top of the list are small freezers, fridges, blenders, juicers, or multicooker</li>
  <li>Notebooks and tablets/ipads - most children are bed ridden and one of the few things they can do is use technology to keep them stimulated.</li>
</ul><hr><p>23/5/22</p><h2>More about Vlad </h2>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_62b44365a70d41389a0002c9fb1c88fa~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_496,h_368,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h6>Vlad, his mum and Yuliya, volunteer we work with.</h6>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_67c1bac6dbb14b89b57a9788fabfde01~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_450,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h6>The wood fired stove where the water is heated.</h6>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_0defbb1b662b4f81bad124dc28ea728f~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_450,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h6>The well where Vlad’s mother draws water from.</h6>
<hr><h2>More about Karolina</h2><p>Karolina urgently needs a new specialized pushchair, she has outgrown her normal stroller and frequent uncontrolled movements of her head mean that she often hurts herself against the sides of the old pushchair. The family doesn’t have money to buy a new one.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_25414838cfba466ba908bc936e0c54ac~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_960,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>This is the cellar where Karolina and her family are hiding during air raids.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_59edc67f75d849b19290d3981bc7adff~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_720,h_960,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p> Explosion not far from the house where they are staying.  </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_50f1e2430cea4efe8b13505211103108~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_960,h_889,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p> Dream pushchair is around GBP 1000, a price unimaginable for Karolina’s mom.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0fe25a_01aa6ce6ffa24ba59a2ed9a8775282e9~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_810,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>